Guide to the World Student Christian Federation Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
- E: Great Britain and Ireland, Series XLIX
  - E500 Organized Lines of Work and Study. Religious Departments and Meetings. General Methods
    - E510 Evangelistic and philanthropic work among students
      - E514 Work for schoolboys and schoolgirls
        - General
          - Conference for Women Teachers in Secondary Schools (Box 197, Folder 1462)
        - E514.1 Camps
          - Materials re. University Women's Camps for Schoolgirls, 1908-1909, 1922-1924 (Box 197, Folder 1463)
          - Materials re. University Camps for Public Schools, 1912, 1914 (Box 197, Folder 1464)
      - E515 Deputation work among the colleges
        - E515.3
          - Wilder. The Bible and Foreign Missions, 1897, 1906 (Box 197, Folder 1465)
      - E518 The individual as citizen. The war. Church and state. Church history
        - Items listed in card catalog (Box 197, Folder 1466)
        - Mott's notes re. British movement, 1914 (Box 197, Folder 1467)
      - E519 Work for foreign students
        - Sadler. Christian Education in Africa and the East, 1924 (Box 197, Folder 1468)
        - Indian Students in England (Box 197, Folder 1468)
        - Report re. the Foyer D'Etudiants, London, 1915 (Box 197, Folder 1468)
    - E520 Devotional and inspirational. The Morning Watch
      - General
        - The Disciple of Prayer, 1915 (Box 197, Folder 1469)
        - Lilley. Worship, 1926 (Box 197, Folder 1469)
        - Seaton. Faith and Prayer, 1928 (Box 197, Folder 1470)
        - Pelly. Aspects of the Holy Communion, 1922 (Box 197, Folder 1470)
        - Southall. A Challenge to Girls, n.d. (Box 198, Folder 1471)
        - Mott. The Secret Prayer Life, 1903 (Box 198, Folder 1471)
        - Mott. Bible Study for Personal Spiritual Growth, n.d. (Box 198, Folder 1471)
        - Mott. Intercessors, 1914 (Box 198, Folder 1471)
        - Horton. Prayer and the Divine source of Power, 1908 (Box 198, Folder 1471)
        - Wilder. United Intercession, n.d. (Box 198, Folder 1471)
      - E522 Days and weeks of prayer
        - E522.1 Calls to prayer
          - SCM calls to prayer, 1899,1908,1917, 1923 (Box 198, Folder 1472)
          - BCCU calls to prayer, 1896-1899 (Box 198, Folder 1473)
          - Student Volunteer Missionary Union calls to prayer, 1895 (Box 198, Folder 1474)
        - E522.2 Prayer cycles, litanies and daily helps
          - Various cycles (BCCU/SCM), n.d. (Box 198, Folder 1475)
          - Various cycles (BCCU/SCM), 1946 (Box 299, Folder 2759)
          - Hubbard. Some Catholic Methods of Prayer, 1925 (Box 198, Folder 1476)
          - Steven. Hints and Helps for Corporate Prayer, 1925 (Box 198, Folder 1476)
        - E522.3 Song books, religious poetry
          - Hymns of the Kingdom, 1923 (Box 198, Folder 1477)
    - E530 Bible Study
      - General
        - Materials re. Bible study in a Christian union, 1898,1911, 1917 (Box 198, Folder 1478)
        - Materials re. Bible study in the SCM, 1897, 1914 (Box 198, Folder 1479)
        - Some Questions on the Christian Attitude to Peace and War, 1934 (Box 299, Folder 2760)
      - E530.1 Bibliography
        - Literature on the Bible, 1914 (Box 198, Folder 1480)
        - Christian Doctrine, 1911 (Box 198, Folder 1480)
      - E531 Bible classes and circles
        - Anderson. College Bible Circles (Box 198, Folder 1480)
      - E531.2 Leadership
        - Tatlow. Leadership of a Bible Circle, 1910 (Box 198, Folder 1480)
      - E532 Text-books
        - Items listed in card catalog (Box 198, Folder 1481)
        - Items listed in card catalog (Box 199, Folder 1482)
      - E533 Outlines from texts
        - General
          - Christianity and the War (Box 200, Folder 1483)
          - Bible Circle Outline (Box 200, Folder 1483)
          - The Essentials of Christianity (Box 200, Folder 1483)
          - Faith and Modern Thought (Box 200, Folder 1483)
          - The Meaning of Christ (Box 200, Folder 1483)
          - The Christian Adventure (Box 200, Folder 1483)
          - Coates. The Life of Christ (Box 200, Folder 1484)
          - Cadoux. The Life of the Historical Jesus (Box 200, Folder 1484)
          - Hutchinson. Thessalonians (Box 200, Folder 1484)
          - Hunter. Studies on Isaiah 1-39 (Box 200, Folder 1484)
          - Perceval. Studies on Isaiah 40-55 (Box 200, Folder 1484)
          - Preston Hanson. The Sermon on the Mount, 1945 (Box 299, Folder 2761)
        - E533.1 For leaders
          - Hints for Bible Circle Leaders (Box 200, Folder 1485)
          - Christian Discipleship and Social Life, 1910 (Box 200, Folder 1485)
          - Problems of Conduct in College (Box 200, Folder 1485)
          - God, the Child and the Teacher (Box 200, Folder 1485)
      - E534 Cycles of study
        - Various cycles (Box 200, Folder 1486)
      - E535 Individual Bible study
        - E535.1 Outlines
          - Annual outlines, 1922-1925 (Box 200, Folder 1487)
          - Cockin. Ephesians (Box 200, Folder 1488)
          - Various outlines (Box 200, Folder 1488)
    - E540 Mission study and service. SVM. YMCA. Foreign Departments
      - General
        - Materials re. formation and purpose of SVM, 1896-1899 (Box 200, Folder 1489-1490)
        - Materials re. nature of mission work (Box 200, Folder 1491)
        - SVM books re. indigenous theology: An Indian Approach to India, 1928 (Box 200, Folder 1492)
        - SVM books re. indigenous theology: Japan Speaks for Herself, 1928 (Box 200, Folder 1492)
        - SVM books re. indigenous theology: Voices From the Near East, 1928 (Box 200, Folder 1492)
        - SVM books re. indigenous theology: China Her Own Interpreter, 1928 (Box 200, Folder 1492)
        - SVM books re. indigenous theology: Thinking With Africa, 1928 (Box 200, Folder 1492)
      - Sources
        - E540.1 Bibliography
          - Missionary books, 1898,1906 (Box 201, Folder 1493)
        - E540.2 Statistics and atlases, charts
          - A Bird's-Eye View of the Foreign Mission Field (Box 201, Folder 1493)
        - E540.3 Handbooks of methods, directories, blanks
          - Declarations of purpose blanks (Box 201, Folder 1494)
          - Dublin United Missionary Campaign, 1924 (Box 299, Folder 2762)
      - E541 Mission study. Methods and organization
        - Hodgkin. Hints on the Study of Missions, 1903 (Box 201, Folder 1495)
        - Spencer. Theological Students and the Missionary Outlook, 1906 (Box 201, Folder 1495)
        - Tatlow. Study of Foreign Missions, 1906 (Box 201, Folder 1495)
        - Tatlow. Reasons for the Study of Foreign Missions, n.d. (Box 201, Folder 1495)
        - Tatlow. Missionary Study in War Time, 1916 (Box 201, Folder 1495)
        - Materials re. mission study and methods (Box 201, Folder 1496)
      - E542 Text-books
        - Items listed in card catalog. (n.b. Items in this section which deal specifically with India have been moved to F(d)542.) (Box 201, Folder 1497)
      - E543 Outlines from texts
        - General
          - Outlines re. mission countries and missions (Box 202, Folder 1498)
          - Outlines re. comparative religion/home missions (Box 202, Folder 1499)
        - E543.1 For leaders
          - Leaders' outlines/suggestions (Box 202, Folder 1500)
      - E544 Mission service. Obligations as to missions implied in Christianity and resting upon the Church
        - General
          - The World Task of the Christian Church, 1925 (Box 202, Folder 1501)
          - The Purpose of God in the Life of the World (Box 202, Folder 1501)
          - Wann. Christianity and the Educated Classes in India, 1908 (Box 202, Folder 1502)
          - Bevan. The New Day in India, 1920 (Box 202, Folder 1502)
          - Mess. How to Back Our Missionaries, 1920 (Box 202, Folder 1502)
          - Speer. The Place of Missions in the Thought of God, n.d. (Box 202, Folder 1502)
          - Spencer. The Missionary Problem and the Denial of Christ in Christendom, 1911 (Box 202, Folder 1502)
          - Martin. The Calling of the Church, 1916 (Box 202, Folder 1502)
        - E544.1 Motives of missions
          - John. The Supreme Motive in Foreign Missions (Box 202, Folder 1503)
        - E544.2 Need for missions
          - Various appeals and descriptions of missions in foreign lands (Box 202, Folder 1504)
        - E544.3 Claims of Christianity over other religions. Comparative religion. Apologetics
          - Axenfield. The Problem of Islam, 1912 (Box 202, Folder 1505)
          - Darbyshire. The Christian Faith and Some Alternatives, 1921 (Box 202, Folder 1505)
          - Hawkridge. The Pilgrim's Quest, 1925 (Box 202, Folder 1505)
          - Hsu. The Philosophy of Confucius, 1926 (Box 202, Folder 1506)
          - Rudra. Christ and Modern India, 1910 (Box 202, Folder 1506)
          - Winslow. The Indian Mystic (Box 202, Folder 1506)
        - E544.4 Needs of support at home in men, money and prayer, and works toward these ends. Student missionary campaigns
          - Speer. Prayer and Missions, 1903 (Box 202, Folder 1507)
          - Warneck. Prayer for Missions, n.d. (Box 202, Folder 1507)
          - The Student Missionary Campaign (Box 202, Folder 1507)
        - E544.41 Prayer cycles for mission work
          - Various cycles, 1924-1926 (Box 203, Folder 1508)
      - E545 Enlistment for life work in missions
        - General
          - Holland. The Call to the World, 1912 (Box 203, Folder 1509)
          - Brockman. If God Permit (Box 203, Folder 1509)
          - Richardson. The Call of the East (Box 203, Folder 1509)
          - Tatlow. Missionary Vocation and the Declaration of the SVMU, 1914 (Box 203, Folder 1509)
          - Winslow. Not Leaders, But Saints and Servants (Box 203, Folder 1509)
          - Pamphlet re. SVMU in relation to schoolgirls (Box 203, Folder 1509)
        - E545.1 Preparation and qualifications
          - Oldham. Student Volunteers and Their Preparation (Box 203, Folder 1510)
        - E545.2 Need for specialists
          - E545.21 Preachers
            - Lenwood. Two Letters from the Mission Field, 1911 (Box 203, Folder 1510)
            - The Appeal of the SVMU to Theological Students, 1907 (Box 203, Folder 1510)
          - E545.23 Teachers
            - Hodgkin. Students and the Foreign Service of the Kingdom of God (Box 203, Folder 1511)
            - Selincourt. Trained Teachers in the Mission Field (Box 203, Folder 1511)
      - E546 Work with women in missionlands and overseas
        - Richardson. Womanhood in the East (Box 203, Folder 1511)
        - Selincourt. The Place of Women in the Modern National Movements of the East, 1912 (Box 203, Folder 1511)
      - E547 Education, secular and religious, of natives in mission lands
        - E547.2 Medical
          - Robin. What It Feels Like, 1926 (Box 203, Folder 1511)
      - E549 History of the student missionary movement as distinguished from the SCM as a whole
        - General
          - Extracts from R.P. Wilder's journal re. origin of SVM, 1900 (Box 203, Folder 1511)
          - Papers re. SVMU Retreat and SVMU, 1909 (Box 203, Folder 1512)
        - E549.1 Reports
          - MacLennan. Twenty Years of Missionary Co-operation, 1927 (Box 203, Folder 1513)
        - E549.11 Reports of progress
          - SVMU, Christ for the World (Box 203, Folder 1513)
        - E549.6 Conferences
          - General
            - Liverpool conference appraisals, 1896,1899 (Box 203, Folder 1514)
          - E549.603 Handbooks, guides, directories, daily bulletins
            - Handbook: International Student Missionary Conference, London, 1900 (Box 203, Folder 1515)
            - Handbook: Student Conference, Liverpool, 1912 (Box 203, Folder 1515)
            - List of Delegates, Liverpool, 1908 (Box 203, Folder 1515)
          - E549.61 Plenary conferences (SVMU International Conferences)
            - Liverpool, 1896 (Box 203, Folder 1516)
            - Liverpool, 1900 (Box 203, Folder 1516)
            - London, 1900 (Box 203, Folder 1516)
            - Edinburgh, 1904 (Box 203, Folder 1516)
            - London, 1904 (Box 203, Folder 1516)
            - Liverpool, 1912 (Box 203, Folder 1516)
          - E549.66 Hymnals, requests for prayer
            - Liverpool (Box 203, Folder 1517)
            - London, 1900 (Box 203, Folder 1517)
          - E549.67 Sundry conferences
            - Report re. London SVMU conference, 1900 (Box 203, Folder 1518)
            - Press items re. Liverpool SVMU conference, 1896 (Box 203, Folder 1519)
            - Scrapbook re. Liverpool SVMU conference, 1896 (Box 203, Folder 1520)
          - E549.69 Student Discussion Conferences
            - Report of SVMU Keswick conference, 1893 (Box 204, Folder 1521)
            - Addresses from SVMU Liverpool conference, 1908 (Box 204, Folder 1521)
    - E550 Social study and service. Community welfare work, religious and philanthropic, outside of student body. Home missions
      - General
        - Pamphlets
          - Miscellaneous pamphlets re. social work (Box 204, Folder 1522)
          - Kirk. A Study of Silent Minds, 1918 (Box 204, Folder 1523)
          - Read. From Field to Factory, 1927 (Box 204, Folder 1523)
          - Rowland. Social Service, 1928 (Box 204, Folder 1524)
          - Tayler. Farm and Factory in China, 1928 (Box 204, Folder 1524)
        - E550.1 Bibliography
          - Spencer. Works on Christianity and Society, 1911 (Box 204, Folder 1525)
          - Early Student Movement issues re. social work, 1900-1907 (Box 204, Folder 1525)
      - E552 Text-books
        - Items listed in card catalog (Box 204, Folder 1526)
      - E553 Outlines from texts
        - General
          - Various outlines re. social work (Box 205, Folder 1527)
        - E553.1 For leaders
          - Outlines re. social work and women's movement (Box 205, Folder 1528)
      - E554 Social service. Obligations as to community service implied in Christianity and resting upon the Church
        - General
          - Balme. The Contribution of Christian Thought to the Science and Practice of Medicine, 1928 (Box 205, Folder 1529)
          - Talbot. Human Brotherhood, 1912 (Box 205, Folder 1529)
        - E544.2 Enlistment of Christian students in professions promotive of community betterment
          - Gilmour. The Vocation of a Doctor (Box 205, Folder 1529)
      - E555A Institutions and Organizations for Social Effort on behalf of students
        - Materials re. Imperial War Relief Fund (Box 205, Folder 1530)
        - Materials re. Ireland, relief efforts, etc., 1922 (Box 205, Folder 1530)
        - Irish Laymen's Missionary Movement - Reports, 1921-1924 (Box 299, Folder 2763)
        - International Student Service, 1926, n.d. (Box 299, Folder 2764)
        - Universities' Relief Committee, 1924 (Box 299, Folder 2765)
      - E556 Social Morality
        - General
          - Andrews. The Opium Evil of India, 1926 (Box 205, Folder 1531)
          - Carter. Facts About Greyhound Racing, 1928 (Box 205, Folder 1531)
          - Gray. Sex Relations Without Marriage, 1928 (Box 205, Folder 1531)
          - Green. Betting and Gambling, 1924 (Box 205, Folder 1531)
          - Perkins. Betting Facts, 1925 (Box 205, Folder 1532)
          - Reason. A Handbook to the Drink Problem, 1926 (Box 205, Folder 1532)
        - E556.1 Economic, political, and moral education of women
          - Fairfield. The Women's Movement (Box 205, Folder 1533)
        - E556.2 Sex education
          - Eddy. Sex and Youth, 1928 (Box 205, Folder 1533)
          - Bisseker. In Confidence: To Boys, 1907 (Box 205, Folder 1533)
        - E556.3 Temperance
          - Astor. Are Temperance Reformers Cranks?, 1922 (Box 205, Folder 1533)
    - E570 Business and publicity. Appeals for financial aid
      - The Money Problem (Box 205, Folder 1534)
      - How Shall I Spend My Money? (Box 205, Folder 1534)
      - Open letter re. finances - SCM, 1914 (Box 205, Folder 1534)
      - Leaflets re. SCM, 1914 (Box 205, Folder 1534)
      - Materials re. finance, 1923-1925, n.d. (Box 299, Folder 2766)
      - Miller. The National Average: A Study in Social Discipline, 1941 (Box 299, Folder 2767)
      - Tatlow. The Finances of a Student Movement, 1925 (Box 299, Folder 2767)
    - E580 Information. Employment Bureaus. Handbook of university information for new students
      - University of Manchester handbook, 1931-1932 (Box 205, Folder 1535)
      - University of Liverpool handbook, 1931-1932 (Box 205, Folder 1535)
  - E600 Associations in Individual Institutions or among Special Classes of Students
    - E610 Colleges, universities and student departments of metropolitan and state associations
      - E611 Objects and field, extension and supervision
        - Article re. Christian activities at Oxford, 1899 (Box 205, Folder 1536)
        - Statement re. Durham Inter-Collegiate Christian Union (Box 205, Folder 1536)
      - E612 Buildings and Rooms
        - Student Movement House report, 1941 (Box 205, Folder 1536)
      - E613 Organization, Incorporation
        - General
          - National Union of Students, 1926 (Box 299, Folder 2768)
        - E613.1 Constitution and membership
          - Oxford Inter-Collegiate Christian Union Rules, 1892 (Box 205, Folder 1536)
      - E615 Organized lines of work and study. Religious departments and meetings. General methods
        - E615.004 Term programs
          - Various university Christian union guides and hand-books, 1911-1913 (Box 206, Folder 1537)
        - E615.1 Evangelistic and philanthropic work among students
          - General
            - Appeals for prayer for evangelistic campaigns at Oxford and Cardiff, 1898, 1912 (Box 206, Folder 1538)
            - Simpson. Hezekiah's Revival Address for meeting at Edinburgh, 1885 (Box 206, Folder 1538)
        - E615.104 Meetings, announcements
          - Cards announcing meetings at various universities, 1899 (Box 206, Folder 1538)
        - E615.106 Song services
          - Hymn leaflet for Edinburgh meetings (Box 206, Folder 1538)
        - E615.19 Work for foreign students
          - A Hostel for East and West (Box 206, Folder 1538)
        - E615.2 Devotional and inspirational
          - E615.22 Days and weeks of prayer
            - Report on meeting for Universal Prayer Day at Edinburgh, 1899 (Box 206, Folder 1539)
          - E615.221 Calls to prayer
            - London Intercollegiate Christian Union card, 1909 (Box 206, Folder 1539)
          - E615.222 Prayer cycles, litanies
            - Manchester University Christ-ian Union prayer sugges-tions, 1912-1913 (Box 206, Folder 1539)
        - E615.3 Bible study
          - E615.31 Bible classes and circles
            - E615.311 Prospectuses and program of courses
              - Cambridge Christian Union prospectus (Box 206, Folder 1540)
        - E615.4 Mission study and service. SVM. YMCA. Foreign departments
          - General
            - Simpson. A Golden Apple in a Silver Basket, 1898 (Box 206, Folder 1540)
          - E615.403 Handbooks of methods, directories, blanks
            - Oxford SVMU muster role, 1897 (Box 206, Folder 1540)
          - E615.404 General Meetings, announcements, programs
            - SVMU meetings, 1892 (Box 206, Folder 1540)
        - E615.8 Handbooks
          - Dublin University Christian Union handbook (Box 206, Folder 1540)
      - E619 History
        - General
          - Simpson. The Year of Grace In the University of Edinburgh, 1885 (Box 206, Folder 1541)
          - Simpson. Spiritual Movement In the University of Edinburgh (article and original), 1885 (Box 206, Folder 1541)
        - E619.1 Reports
          - Manchester University Christian Unions, 1911-1912 (Box 206, Folder 1542)
          - Oxford Christian Union, 1895-1897 (Box 206, Folder 1542)
        - E619.5 Periodicals
          - The Student Movement (St. Andrews), 1905-1906 (Box 206, Folder 1543)
          - The Student Movement (Edinburgh), 1904,1905 (Box 206, Folder 1544)
          - The Student Movement (Oxford) (Box 206, Folder 1545-1546)
        - E619.6 Conventions and conferences
          - E619.61 Plenary conferences (programs)
            - Liverpool Christian Union, 1912 (Box 206, Folder 1547)
            - Cambridge Christian Union, 1898 (Box 206, Folder 1547)
          - E619.69 Student Discussion Conferences
            - Dublin. Irish Christian Fellowship, Report - Irish Problems, 1919 (Box 206, Folder 1547)
    - E620 Professional Schools
      - General
        - Materials re. SCM work among theological students, 1924-1926 (Box 206, Folder 1548)
        - SCM Commission on Work of the Theological College Department, 1914-1915 (Box 206, Folder 1549-1550)
      - E622 Medical
        - London School of Medicine for Women Christian Union Handbook, 1912-1913 (Box 207, Folder 1551)
    - E630 Secondary Schools
      - Materials re. work in girls' schools and with teachers in conjunction with YWCA (Box 207, Folder 1551)
    - E660 Associations among special classes
      - E661 Art Schools
        - Sundry documents, 1898-1914 (Box 207, Folder 1552)
        - The Student Movement periodical, Fine Art students' edition, 1905-1907 (Box 207, Folder 1553)
        - The Student Movement, Art Students' supplement, 1905-1910 (Box 207, Folder 1554-1555)
      - E664 Auxiliary Associations of non-students
        - Roxby. The English Civic Universities in Relation to World Problems, 1921 (Box 207, Folder 1556)
        - Conferences from Leeds, 1928 (Box 207, Folder 1556)
        - Auxiliary Movement Book of Fellowship, 1931 (Box 207, Folder 1557)
        - Auxiliary Movement membership list, 1914 (Box 207, Folder 1557)
    - E690 Foreign
      - Work for foreign student refugees, 1915-1918 (Box 207, Folder 1558)
      - Materials re. SCM International Relationship Committee, 1922-1924 (Box 208, Folder 1559)
      - Materials re. foreign student refugees, 1917-1919 (Box 208, Folder 1560)
      - E691 Objects and field
        - Proposed recommendations to the Chinese Students' Christian Union in Great Britain and Ireland (Box 208, Folder 1561)
      - E695 Organized lines of work and study
        - E695.3 Bible study
          - E695.34 Cycles of study E695.34Cycles of study
            - Chinese SCM cycle, 1916 (Box 208, Folder 1562)
        - E695.7 Appeals for financial aid
          - Chinese SCM circular letter appealing for funds, 1919 (Box 208, Folder 1562)
      - E696 Associations in individual institutions or among special classes of students
        - E696.9 Foreign
          - Report of special Delegation of Serbian students at First Swanwick Conference, 1919 (Box 208, Folder 1562)
      - E699 History
        - E699.1 Reports
          - General
            - Indian Students' Union and Hostel, annual reports, 1920-1927 (Box 208, Folder 1563)
            - Papers re. Indian Students' Union and Hostel, 1923,1924 (Box 208, Folder 1564)
          - E699.11 Reports of progress
            - E699.111 Directories
              - Chinese SCU, 1913,1916 (Box 208, Folder 1565)
        - E699.5 Periodicals
          - Subscription blank for The Indus (Box 208, Folder 1565)
          - Ch'uen Tao, 1915-1929 (Box 208, Folder 1566-1567)
        - E699.6 Conferences
          - E699.61 Plenary conferences
            - Chinese SCU report on Swanwick, 1913 (Box 208, Folder 1568)
          - E699.67 Sundry conferences
            - Kerr. Democracy (address at Indian Students' Union and Hostel), 1925 (Box 208, Folder 1568)
          - E699.69 Student Discussion Conferences
            - The Hayes Conference, Swanwick, 1919 (Box 208, Folder 1568)
  - E700 Student Life in General Outside the Federation
    - General
      - List of Corps of Christian Volunteers, 1895 (Box 208, Folder 1569)
      - Ladstone. Letters addressed to the Corps of Christian Volunteers, 1894,1895 (Box 208, Folder 1569)